Mohini Rana

2147 Newhall Street, Santa Clara, CA - 95050 | 781.952.9913 | mrana@scu.edu | www.linkedin.com/mohini-rana

SUMMARY

I am a Machine Learning and Data Science enthusiast with 2+ years of experience using data pre-processing, predictive modeling with time series forecasting algorithms to solve challenging business problems. Proven skills in leading large teams, with a focus on optimizing development processes to enhance efficiency and accuracy for data-driven solutions.

EDUCATION

Master's in Computer Science and Engineering | Santa Clara University, USA| **GPA - 4/4**Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology) | University of Pune, India | **GPA - 3.48/4**September 2021 - June 2023

July 2015 - June 2019

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ISS Peer Ambassador, Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, USA

January 2022 - Present

- My roles and responsibilities include being at the front desk and helping students with their document pick up, assisting in scheduling meetings, and answering students with their questions.
- I assist the International Students and Scholars Director and the ISS Advisors with their appointment scheduling, other tasks as assigned.

Publishing Assistant, Miller Center, Santa Clara University, Santa Clara, USA

November 2021 - December 2021

• Assisted the Miller Center team to create, design, and organize several pages of 10-15 books using **BookWright** Software.

Associate Consultant - Data Scientist, Supply Chain Apps, Bristlecone, Pune, India July 2019 - September 2021

- Predictive Analytics Built 78% accurate models in **Python** for demand forecasting using time series and machine learning for tasks involving the prediction of sales data which helped to secure two clients.
- Gained hands-on experience in data pre-processing, data cleaning, and handling missing data.
- Worked on six POCs and was also responsible for carrying out extensive research-related activities using **MS Excel** involving competitor analysis, providing insights through my presentations in **Tableau** and **PowerPoint** which helped in securing two big clients.
- Received a Brilliant Beginner Award and two SPOT awards for my contributions to the project and several events.

ML Engineer Intern, DigitalMain, Pune, India

March 2018 - June 2019

- Worked as an active member of the team for the AI/ML Innovation Project Similar Question Identification using Natural Language Processing and Neural Networks.
- I built a POC in **Python** to reduce the redundancy of questions asked on Quora and find the similarity score of two questions.
- After running several different models CNN, RNN, the accuracy was above 82% and a reduced log loss of 36%.
- I published my survey paper in the IJRAR Journal. https://github.com/MohiniRana/My-Profile/blob/main/Survey%20Paper.pdf

Business Analyst Intern, Vidya Online Services, Pune, India

July 2018 - October 2018

- Prepared documents like Business Requirement documents, Functional Requirement documents for clients, and applied knowledge of **Software Development Life Cycle** and **Project Management**.
- Created a User Manual Document for one of the clients for their website.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Lightweight Mutual Authentication for IOT & Its Applications using RSA and ECC
- Attendance Monitoring System website using HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Java
- Periodic Table using SQL and Java

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python for Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Data Science, Deep Learning, and Neural Networks, Tableau, R Programming, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3, Canva, BookWright, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Word

AFFILIATIONS

Held positions of Technical Secretary, Technical Head, and Discipline Head during the Undergrad College Fest Alacrity, Treasurer of IT Engg Dept., General Secretary of First-Year Dept., and Internshala Student Partner for 3 consecutive semesters.

INTERESTS

Reading, solving puzzles, learning new software tools to improve personal efficiency and effectiveness, volunteering